const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"Which of the following is the laser used for treating posterior capsular opacification in adults?","answers":[{"option":"Holmium laser","bool":false},{"option":"Femtosecond laser","bool":false},{"option":"Excimer laser","bool":false},{"option":"Argon laser","bool":false},{"option":"Nd-YAG laser","bool":true}]},{"id":1,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"What is the most common type of entropion?","answers":[{"option":"Cicatricial","bool":false},{"option":"Senile","bool":true},{"option":"Congenital","bool":false},{"option":"Paralytic","bool":false},{"option":"Spastic","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"Complicated cataracts are complications of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Diabetic retinopathy","bool":false},{"option":"Phacoantigenic uveitis","bool":false},{"option":"Phacomorphic glaucoma","bool":false},{"option":"Phacolytic glaucoma","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior uveitis","bool":true}]},{"id":3,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"The medial rectus is supplied by which nerve?","answers":[{"option":"Cranial nerve X","bool":false},{"option":"Cranial nerve IV","bool":false},{"option":"Cranial nerve VI","bool":false},{"option":"Cranial nerve V","bool":false},{"option":"Cranial nerve III","bool":true}]},{"id":4,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"The superior oblique muscle is supplied by which nerve?","answers":[{"option":"Cranial nerve VI","bool":false},{"option":"Cranial nerve X","bool":false},{"option":"Cranial nerve IV","bool":true},{"option":"Cranial nerve III","bool":false},{"option":"Cranial nerve V","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"What is the function of the inferior oblique muscle?","answers":[{"option":"To move the eyeball laterally","bool":false},{"option":"To move the eyeball upwards","bool":false},{"option":"To move the eyeball downward and outward","bool":false},{"option":"To move the eyeball medially","bool":false},{"option":"To move the eyeball upward and outward","bool":true}]},{"id":6,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"Which of the following extraocular muscles has the longest tendon?","answers":[{"option":"Medial rectus","bool":false},{"option":"Superior rectus","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior oblique","bool":false},{"option":"Superior oblique","bool":true},{"option":"Lateral rectus","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"In which nucleus of the thalamus does the optic tract end?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral geniculate body","bool":true},{"option":"Medial geniculate body","bool":false},{"option":"Nucleus tractus solitarius","bool":false},{"option":"Edingerâ€“Westphal nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Occulomotor nucleus","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"Probing is the recommended treatment for congenital nasolacrimal duct obstruction. What is the age of the infant after which probing should be performed?","answers":[{"option":"6 years","bool":false},{"option":"18 months","bool":false},{"option":"6 months","bool":false},{"option":"12 months","bool":true},{"option":"2 years","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"Which of the following is incorrect regarding orbit?","answers":[{"option":"It is directed posterolaterally","bool":false},{"option":"It is a pyramid shaped cavity","bool":false},{"option":"The floor is formed by the maxilla, palatine and zygomatic bones.","bool":false},{"option":"It contains branches of trigeminal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"The optic canal forms the base of the cavity","bool":true}]},{"id":10,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"What is the treatment of stye?","answers":[{"option":"Evacuation of pus","bool":false},{"option":"Topical antibiotics","bool":false},{"option":"Analgesics for relief of pain","bool":false},{"option":"Warm compresses applied for 10 minutes, 5 times daily","bool":false},{"option":"All of these","bool":true}]},{"id":11,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"What is the treatment for resistant trichiasis?","answers":[{"option":"Electrolysis","bool":false},{"option":"Argon laser","bool":false},{"option":"Cryotherapy","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior lamellar and wedge resection","bool":true},{"option":"Epilation","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"The lateral rectus muscle is supplied by which of the following cranial nerves?","answers":[{"option":"Abducens nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Maxillary nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Trochlear nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Oculomotor nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Facial nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"What is the most common cause of preventable blindness?","answers":[{"option":"Diabetic retinopathy","bool":false},{"option":"Glaucoma","bool":false},{"option":"Cataract","bool":false},{"option":"Trachoma","bool":true},{"option":"Bacterial corneal ulcer","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"Which of the following diseases is caused by unhygienic conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Glaucoma","bool":false},{"option":"Diabetic retinopathy","bool":false},{"option":"Trachoma","bool":true},{"option":"Fungal keratitis","bool":false},{"option":"Cataract","bool":false}]},{"id":15,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"Which of the following antiviral drugs is least toxic?","answers":[{"option":"Foscarnet","bool":false},{"option":"Zidovudine","bool":false},{"option":"Cidofovir","bool":false},{"option":"Ganciclovir","bool":false},{"option":"Acyclovir","bool":true}]},{"id":16,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"Which of the following is a characteristic feature usually only present in herpes simplex virus (HSV) keratitis?","answers":[{"option":"Redness","bool":false},{"option":"Lacrimation","bool":false},{"option":"Pain","bool":false},{"option":"Photophobia","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased corneal sensitivity","bool":true}]},{"id":17,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"Which of the following is a common side effect of long-term systemic steroid use?","answers":[{"option":"Uveitis","bool":false},{"option":"Fundus dystrophy","bool":false},{"option":"Cataract","bool":true},{"option":"Keratitis","bool":false},{"option":"Glaucoma","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"A 2-month-old male child is brought to the clinic by his parents. He is found to have problems with lacrimation and photophobia. The cornea of both eyes is also large and hazy. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Congenital glaucoma","bool":true},{"option":"Megalocornea","bool":false},{"option":"High myopia","bool":false},{"option":"Nasolacrimal duct obstruction","bool":false},{"option":"Ocular birth trauma","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"Which of the following is the mode of action of alpha-2 agonists?","answers":[{"option":"Constriction of pupil","bool":false},{"option":"Decreases trabecular outflow","bool":false},{"option":"Decreases aqueous production and increases uveoscleral outflow","bool":true},{"option":"Increases aqueous outflow","bool":false},{"option":"Decreases aqueous production","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"According to WHO, blindness is defined as visual acuity of or less than which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"3/60","bool":true},{"option":"6/60","bool":false},{"option":"Counting fingers only","bool":false},{"option":"No perception of light","bool":false},{"option":"6/18","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"Which of the following is the most popular refractive procedure for the correction of myopia?","answers":[{"option":"LASIK","bool":true},{"option":"PRK","bool":false},{"option":"Clear lens extraction","bool":false},{"option":"LASEK","bool":false},{"option":"Phakic posterior chamber implant","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"An 11-year-old boy presented with a chronic history of itching and watering eyes, photophobia, and marked redness in both eyes. On examination, visual acuity was 20/20 for both eyes. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Mucopurulent conjunctivitis","bool":false},{"option":"Vernal keratoconjunctivitis","bool":true},{"option":"Purulent conjunctivitis","bool":false},{"option":"Pharyngoconjunctival fever","bool":false},{"option":"Membranous conjunctivitis","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"Which statement is correct regarding vernal keratoconjunctivitis?","answers":[{"option":"Usually there is no genetic history involved","bool":false},{"option":"It is more common in females","bool":false},{"option":"It usually occurs in children","bool":true},{"option":"It usually occurs in adults","bool":false},{"option":"It is a type II hypersensitivity reaction","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"Which type of scleritis usually presents with visual impairment and proptosis?","answers":[{"option":"Diffuse  scleritis","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior necrotizing  scleritis without inflammation","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior scleritis","bool":true},{"option":"Nodular  scleritis","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior necrotizing  scleritis with inflammation","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"Which one of them is not a distinguishing feature between episcleritis and scleritis?","answers":[{"option":"Visual impairment","bool":false},{"option":"Systemic association","bool":false},{"option":"Mobility of lesion","bool":false},{"option":"Phenylephrine test","bool":false},{"option":"Redness of eye","bool":true}]},{"id":26,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"What is the most common type of cataract in diabetes?","answers":[{"option":"Total cataract","bool":false},{"option":"Cortical cataract","bool":false},{"option":"Snowflake capsular cataract","bool":true},{"option":"Sunflower cataract","bool":false},{"option":"Nuclear cataract","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"What is the mechanism of action of a topical carbonic anhydrase inhibitor on the eye?","answers":[{"option":"Contracts ciliary muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Blocks the trabecular meshwork","bool":false},{"option":"Decreases aqueous secretion","bool":true},{"option":"Contracts pupillary sphincter muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Increases aqueous outflow","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"What is the treatment of choice in primary open angle glaucoma if intraocular pressure (IOP) is uncontrolled despite maximally tolerated medical therapy?","answers":[{"option":"Trabeculectomy","bool":false},{"option":"Laser","bool":true},{"option":"Increase the dosage of drugs or give them in combination","bool":false},{"option":"Viscocanalostomy","bool":false},{"option":"Deep  sclerotomy","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"Which class of drugs are most commonly associated with the development of secondary cataracts?","answers":[{"option":"Steroids","bool":true},{"option":"Topical antibiotics","bool":false},{"option":"Miotics","bool":false},{"option":"Carbonic anhydrase inhibitors","bool":false},{"option":"Beta blockers","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"What is the most probable cause of congenital glaucoma?","answers":[{"option":"Iridocyclitis","bool":false},{"option":"Deposition of pigments","bool":false},{"option":"Corneal ulcer","bool":false},{"option":"Developmental defect of angle","bool":true},{"option":"Increased production of aqueous humour","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"What is the duration of action of tropicamide as a cycloplegic?","answers":[{"option":"4-10 hours","bool":true},{"option":"48 hours","bool":false},{"option":"12 hours","bool":false},{"option":"7 days","bool":false},{"option":"1-2 hours","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"Which feature will be observed in the proliferative stage of diabetic retinopathy?","answers":[{"option":"Hard exudates","bool":false},{"option":"Microaneurysms","bool":false},{"option":"Flame shaped hemorrhages","bool":false},{"option":"Cotton wool spots","bool":false},{"option":"Retinal neovascularization","bool":true}]},{"id":33,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"Which of the following is a feature of background diabetic retinopathy?","answers":[{"option":"Microaneursyms","bool":true},{"option":"Retinal neovascularization","bool":false},{"option":"Vitreous hemorrhage","bool":false},{"option":"Cotton wool spots","bool":false},{"option":"Tractional retinal detachment","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"Which of the following is a common ophthalmologic side effect of systemic steroid therapy?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior uveitis","bool":false},{"option":"Hemangioma","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior uveitis","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior subcapsular cataract","bool":true},{"option":"Scleritis","bool":false}]},{"id":35,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"Bacterial keratitis is treated with which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Visible light laser","bool":false},{"option":"Topical antibiotics","bool":true},{"option":"Topical steroids","bool":false},{"option":"UV laser","bool":false},{"option":"Topical NSAIDs","bool":false}]},{"id":36,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"Which of the following is the most prevalent cause of blindness?","answers":[{"option":"Cataract","bool":true},{"option":"Aphakia","bool":false},{"option":"Corneal opacities","bool":false},{"option":"Glaucoma","bool":false},{"option":"Diabetic retinopathy","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"Which of the following systemic diseases is closely associated with episcleritis?","answers":[{"option":"Rheumatoid arthritis","bool":true},{"option":"Behcet disease","bool":false},{"option":"Ankylosing spondylitis","bool":false},{"option":"Crohns disease","bool":false},{"option":"Sarcoidosis","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"Which wall of the orbit is the strongest?","answers":[{"option":"Medial","bool":false},{"option":"Floor","bool":false},{"option":"Base","bool":false},{"option":"Roof","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral","bool":true}]},{"id":39,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"Which of the following bones make the roof of the orbit?","answers":[{"option":"The zygomatic bone and greater wing of the sphenoid","bool":false},{"option":"The ethmoid and maxilla","bool":false},{"option":"The maxilla, palatine and zygomatic bones","bool":false},{"option":"The greater wing of sphenoid only","bool":false},{"option":"The frontal bone and the lesser wing of the sphenoid","bool":true}]},{"id":40,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"Which complication among the following occurs in multiple sclerosis?","answers":[{"option":"Corneal cataract","bool":false},{"option":"Papilloedema","bool":false},{"option":"Hordeolum externum","bool":false},{"option":"Blepharitis","bool":false},{"option":"Optic neuritis","bool":true}]},{"id":41,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"What is the most common presentation of retinoblastoma?","answers":[{"option":"Redness of eye","bool":false},{"option":"Lacrimation","bool":false},{"option":"Leukocoria","bool":true},{"option":"Squint","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased vision","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"A 40-year-old adult presented to the clinic with bilateral proptosis. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Lacrimal gland tumour","bool":false},{"option":"Orbital cellulitis","bool":false},{"option":"Orbital lymphoma","bool":false},{"option":"Thyroid ophthalmopathy due to Graves disease","bool":true},{"option":"Mucormycosis","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"What is the most common refractive disorder?","answers":[{"option":"Pathological myopia","bool":false},{"option":"Simple myopia","bool":true},{"option":"Congenital myopia","bool":false},{"option":"Astigmatism","bool":false},{"option":"Hypermetropia","bool":false}]},{"id":44,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"What is the central change characterized as a dark pigmented lesion in the macula due to hemorrhage in pathological myopia called?","answers":[{"option":"Lacquer cracks","bool":false},{"option":"Staphyloma","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrops","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudopapilloedema","bool":false},{"option":"Foster-Fuchs spot","bool":true}]},{"id":45,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"What are the breaks in Bruch's membrane in pathological myopia called?","answers":[{"option":"Staphylomas","bool":false},{"option":"Cotton wool spots","bool":false},{"option":"Lacquer cracks","bool":true},{"option":"Hard exudates","bool":false},{"option":"Foster-Fuchs spots","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"What is the usual age for the development of presbyopia in emmetropes?","answers":[{"option":"50 years","bool":false},{"option":"60 years","bool":false},{"option":"55 years","bool":false},{"option":"40 years","bool":true},{"option":"20 years","bool":false}]},{"id":47,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"The horizontal movement of the eyeball is a function of which of the following muscles?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral rectus","bool":false},{"option":"Medial rectus","bool":false},{"option":"Superior oblique","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior oblique","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral and medial recti","bool":true}]},{"id":48,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"Which of the following is the most common cause of blindness in Pakistan?","answers":[{"option":"Glaucoma","bool":false},{"option":"Malignancy","bool":false},{"option":"Diabetic retinopathy","bool":false},{"option":"Cataract","bool":true},{"option":"Trauma","bool":false}]},{"id":49,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"Which of the following statements is true about basal cell carcinoma?","answers":[{"option":"It is a benign tumor","bool":false},{"option":"It is the least common malignancy","bool":false},{"option":"It is not locally invasive","bool":false},{"option":"It arises from nerve sheath","bool":false},{"option":"It is non metastasizing","bool":true}]},{"id":50,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"Which of the following is the weakest wall of the orbit?","answers":[{"option":"Medial wall","bool":false},{"option":"Roof","bool":false},{"option":"Floor","bool":true},{"option":"Lateral wall","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior wall","bool":false}]},{"id":51,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"Which of the following conditions is associated with Eales disease?","answers":[{"option":"Hepatitis","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberculosis","bool":true},{"option":"Pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Hypertension","bool":false},{"option":"Diabetes","bool":false}]},{"id":52,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"Which of the following is the most dangerous foreign body for the eye?","answers":[{"option":"Iron","bool":true},{"option":"Copper","bool":false},{"option":"Glass","bool":false},{"option":"Plastic","bool":false},{"option":"Coal","bool":false}]},{"id":53,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"What is the test for the estimation of the angle of esophoria?","answers":[{"option":"Maddox rod test","bool":false},{"option":"Cover-uncover test","bool":false},{"option":"Hirschberg test","bool":true},{"option":"Maddox wing test","bool":false},{"option":"Optical Coherence Tomography (OCT)","bool":false}]},{"id":54,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"What is the most probable cause of a pseudosquint?","answers":[{"option":"Narrowing of the anterior chamber angle","bool":false},{"option":"Prominent epicanthal fold","bool":true},{"option":"Change in curvature of cornea","bool":false},{"option":"Conjunctivitis","bool":false},{"option":"Increase in the collagen fibres of stroma","bool":false}]},{"id":55,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"What is the presentation of primary open-angle glaucoma?","answers":[{"option":"Painless loss of vision","bool":true},{"option":"Patient is usually symptom free","bool":false},{"option":"Painful loss of vision","bool":false},{"option":"Periodic episodes of blurred vision and halos","bool":false},{"option":"Buphthalmos","bool":false}]},{"id":56,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"What is the most common cause of cataracts in young adults?","answers":[{"option":"Senility","bool":false},{"option":"Hypothyroidism","bool":false},{"option":"Diabetes mellitus","bool":false},{"option":"Radiation","bool":false},{"option":"Trauma","bool":true}]},{"id":57,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"Which of the following is not used as a vitreous substitute?","answers":[{"option":"Silicone oil","bool":false},{"option":"Ringer's lactate","bool":false},{"option":"Sterile air","bool":false},{"option":"Methylcellulose","bool":true},{"option":"Expandable gas","bool":false}]},{"id":58,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"Which class of drugs does tropicamide belong to?","answers":[{"option":"Cholinergic antagonists","bool":true},{"option":"Steroids","bool":false},{"option":"Anti inflammatory","bool":false},{"option":"Cholinergic agonists","bool":false},{"option":"Topical antibiotics","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"What is the treatment for hyphema?","answers":[{"option":"Antiglaucoma drugs + atropine + topical steroids","bool":true},{"option":"NSAIDs","bool":false},{"option":"Topical antibiotics + atropine","bool":false},{"option":"Warfarin","bool":false},{"option":"Aspirin","bool":false}]},{"id":60,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"Which one of the following is a clinical feature of viral keratitis?","answers":[{"option":"Satellite lesions","bool":false},{"option":"Geographical ulcer","bool":true},{"option":"Feathery edge ulcer","bool":false},{"option":"Snowflake cataract","bool":false},{"option":"Sunflower cataract","bool":false}]},{"id":61,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"Which one of the following is the most dreadful complication of a corneal ulcer?","answers":[{"option":"Perforation","bool":true},{"option":"Descemetocele","bool":false},{"option":"Toxic iridocyclitis","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior uveitis","bool":false},{"option":"Secondary glaucoma","bool":false}]},{"id":62,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"What is the usual age range of a patient who develops vision loss because of diabetic retinopathy?","answers":[{"option":"10-25  years","bool":false},{"option":"70 years and above","bool":false},{"option":"20-40  years","bool":false},{"option":"50-75  years","bool":false},{"option":"25-74 years","bool":true}]},{"id":63,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"Which of the following disease presents with the characteristic T-sign on ultrasonography?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior scleritis","bool":false},{"option":"Congenital glaucoma","bool":false},{"option":"Cataract due to diabetes","bool":false},{"option":"Episcleritis","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior scleritis","bool":true}]},{"id":64,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"What is the age at which pathological myopia begins?","answers":[{"option":"15-20 years","bool":false},{"option":"50- 70 years","bool":false},{"option":"25-50 years","bool":false},{"option":"30-40 years","bool":false},{"option":"5-10 years","bool":true}]},{"id":65,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"What is the length of the medial rectus muscle?","answers":[{"option":"7.5 mm","bool":false},{"option":"6.5 mm","bool":false},{"option":"10 mm","bool":false},{"option":"12.5 mm","bool":false},{"option":"5.5 mm","bool":true}]},{"id":66,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"What is the approximate refractive power of the cornea?","answers":[{"option":"+2 diopters","bool":false},{"option":"+60 diopters","bool":false},{"option":"+ 57 diopters","bool":false},{"option":"+49 diopters","bool":false},{"option":"+43 diopters","bool":true}]},{"id":67,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"Terminal bulbs with dendritic ulcers on the cornea occur due to which of the following pathogens?","answers":[{"option":"Herpes simplex virus","bool":true},{"option":"Varicella zoster virus","bool":false},{"option":"Herpes zoster virus","bool":false},{"option":"Adenovirus","bool":false},{"option":"Acanthamoeba","bool":false}]},{"id":68,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"What does pachymetry measure?","answers":[{"option":"Intraocular pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Depth of anterior chamber","bool":false},{"option":"Angle of deviation","bool":false},{"option":"Total strabismus","bool":false},{"option":"Corneal thickness","bool":true}]},{"id":69,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"What is the treatment of subretinal neovascularization?","answers":[{"option":"Anti-VEGF","bool":true},{"option":"Occlusion therapy","bool":false},{"option":"Pars plana vitrectomy","bool":false},{"option":"Phacoemulsification","bool":false},{"option":"Keratoplasty","bool":false}]},{"id":70,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"What is the principal cause of vision loss worldwide between the ages of 25-74 years?","answers":[{"option":"Glaucoma","bool":false},{"option":"Refractive errors","bool":false},{"option":"Trauma","bool":false},{"option":"Cataract","bool":false},{"option":"Diabetic retinopathy","bool":true}]},{"id":71,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"Which of the following is incorrect regarding papilloedema?","answers":[{"option":"Incomplete macular star","bool":false},{"option":"Splinter hemorrhages may be present","bool":false},{"option":"Normal visual acuity","bool":false},{"option":"Pupils are round and reactive","bool":false},{"option":"Clear margins observed on the optic disc","bool":true}]},{"id":72,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"A yellow-white bulbar mass on the conjunctiva is what condition?","answers":[{"option":"Pseudopterygium","bool":false},{"option":"Pinguecula","bool":true},{"option":"Xerophthalmia","bool":false},{"option":"Pterygium","bool":false},{"option":"Phlyctenulosis","bool":false}]},{"id":73,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"Biometry is a method for power calculation of intraocular lenses. What two parameters are used in it?","answers":[{"option":"Perimetry and gonioscopy","bool":false},{"option":"Keratometry and axial length","bool":true},{"option":"Retinoscopy and keratometry","bool":false},{"option":"Pachymetry and tonometry","bool":false},{"option":"Angle deviation and ophthalmoscopy","bool":false}]},{"id":74,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"Which of the following is not used to treat branched retinal vein occlusion (BRVO)?","answers":[{"option":"Intravitreal triamcinalone","bool":false},{"option":"Prednisolone","bool":false},{"option":"Grid pattern photocoagulation","bool":false},{"option":"Panretinal photocoagulation","bool":true},{"option":"Anti-VEGF","bool":false}]},{"id":75,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"Power by which objects are distinguished is known as what?","answers":[{"option":"Tonometry","bool":false},{"option":"Visual acuity","bool":true},{"option":"Angle deviation","bool":false},{"option":"Gonioscopy","bool":false},{"option":"Keratometry","bool":false}]},{"id":76,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"Arteritic anterior ischemic optic neuropathy is seen in which disease?","answers":[{"option":"Multiple sclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"Giant cell arteritis","bool":true},{"option":"Papilledema","bool":false},{"option":"Optic disc edema","bool":false},{"option":"Papillitis","bool":false}]},{"id":77,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"During probing of the nasoclacrimal duct what structure causes resistance to the probe?","answers":[{"option":"Canaliculus","bool":false},{"option":"Punctum","bool":false},{"option":"Upper membrane","bool":false},{"option":"Lacrimal sac","bool":false},{"option":"Lower membrane","bool":true}]},{"id":78,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"The cherry-red macula is a classic sign of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Retinopathy of prematurity","bool":false},{"option":"Ischemic central vein occlusion","bool":false},{"option":"Central retinal vein occlusion (CRVO)","bool":false},{"option":"Central retinal artery occlusion (CRAO)","bool":true},{"option":"Branched retinal vein occlusion (BRVO)","bool":false}]},{"id":79,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"Which of the following features distinguishes neurological diseases from glaucoma?","answers":[{"option":"Respect vertical meridian","bool":true},{"option":"Respect horizontal meridian","bool":false},{"option":"Pupil involvement","bool":false},{"option":"Systemic signs","bool":false},{"option":"Photophobia","bool":false}]},{"id":80,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"Which of the following statements correctly describe 'Posterior vitreous detachment'?","answers":[{"option":"Separation of the cortical vitreous from the retina posterior to ora serrata","bool":true},{"option":"Detachment of vitreous membrane due to posterior segment trauma","bool":false},{"option":"Contraction of vitreoretinal membrane","bool":false},{"option":"Separation of sensory retina from pigment epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"Vitreous detachment due to hemorrhage","bool":false}]},{"id":81,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"Which of the following is not true regarding retrobulbar optic neuritis?","answers":[{"option":"Vision loss is subacute developing over 2-7 days","bool":false},{"option":"Papillitis is present","bool":true},{"option":"Color vision is affected","bool":false},{"option":"Vision begins to improve spontaneously","bool":false},{"option":"It is a painful condition","bool":false}]},{"id":82,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"Which of the following does not happen in a nuclear cataract?","answers":[{"option":"Hypermetropic shift","bool":true},{"option":"Usually occurs in increased age","bool":false},{"option":"Lens is sclerosed","bool":false},{"option":"Fibers undergo dehydration","bool":false},{"option":"Lens loses elasticity","bool":false}]},{"id":83,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"Which of the following is not true regarding the levator palpebrae superioris muscle?","answers":[{"option":"The medial horn inserts into the orbital tubercle","bool":true},{"option":"Blood supply is by the ophthalmic artery","bool":false},{"option":"Arises from the lesser wing of sphenoid","bool":false},{"option":"Supplied by the oculomotor nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Its tendon blends with the superior rectus muscle","bool":false}]},{"id":84,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"Which of the following is defined as blindness according to the World Health Organization (WHO)?","answers":[{"option":"Visual field less than 10Â°","bool":true},{"option":"Visual field of 45Â°","bool":false},{"option":"Visual field of 10Â°","bool":false},{"option":"Visual field less than 90Â°","bool":false},{"option":"Visual field of 30Â°","bool":false}]},{"id":85,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"A 30-year-old female presents to the clinic with complaints of tearing and itching in the eyes. Ophthalmologic examination reveals a lesion in the conjunctiva that is hard, red, elevated, and surrounded by hyperemia. She has a history of chronic blepharitis. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Keratitis","bool":false},{"option":"Pinguecula","bool":false},{"option":"Squamous cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Pterygium","bool":false},{"option":"Phlyctenulosis","bool":true}]},{"id":86,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"Cover-uncover tests depend on which phenomenon?","answers":[{"option":"Accommodation","bool":false},{"option":"Heterochromia","bool":false},{"option":"Fixation","bool":true},{"option":"Congestion","bool":false},{"option":"Convergence","bool":false}]},{"id":87,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"Which of the following is true regarding phacoemulsification?","answers":[{"option":"It uses a handheld ultrasonic probe to disintegrate the nucleus","bool":true},{"option":"A separate incision is required for insertion of the lens","bool":false},{"option":"Extraction of the entire lens and its capsule","bool":false},{"option":"Does not preserve the posterior capsule","bool":false},{"option":"Incision is always on the cornea","bool":false}]},{"id":88,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"Which of the following is associated with scleritis?","answers":[{"option":"Cataract surgery","bool":false},{"option":"Allergy","bool":false},{"option":"Multiple sclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"Rheumatoid arthritis","bool":true},{"option":"Trauma","bool":false}]},{"id":89,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"Pupil sparing 3rd nerve palsy is seen in which of the following conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Tumors","bool":false},{"option":"Aneurysm","bool":false},{"option":"Diabetes mellitus","bool":true},{"option":"Infection","bool":false},{"option":"Trauma","bool":false}]},{"id":90,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"Which of the following visual field defects will be seen in end-stage glaucoma?","answers":[{"option":"Arcuate scotoma","bool":false},{"option":"Tunnel vision","bool":true},{"option":"Nasal scotoma","bool":false},{"option":"Paracentral scotoma","bool":false},{"option":"Nasal step","bool":false}]},{"id":91,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"Which of the following features is not characteristic of background (non-proliferative) diabetic retinopathy?","answers":[{"option":"Cotton wool spots","bool":false},{"option":"Microaneurysms","bool":false},{"option":"Vitreous hemorrhage","bool":true},{"option":"Retinal edema","bool":false},{"option":"Hard exudates","bool":false}]},{"id":92,"info":"4th-year/eye/2019","question":"Where does the light focus in cases of hypermetropia?","answers":[{"option":"In front of the retina","bool":false},{"option":"Image is not formed","bool":false},{"option":"Behind the retina","bool":true},{"option":"Multiple points on the retina","bool":false},{"option":"Image is formed on the center but the brain does not perceive it","bool":false}]}]
export default arr